<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<locale>
    <string name="en_US">English</string>
    <string name="de_DE">German</string>
    <string name="app_name">Freezing Archer</string>
    <string name="inventory">Inventory</string>
    <string name="drop">Drop</string>
    <string name="use">Use</string>
    <string name="rotate">Rotate</string>
    <string name="pause">Pause</string>
    <string name="back_to_game">Back to game</string>
    <string name="quit_game">Quit game</string>
    <string name="you_survived">You survived</string>
    <string name="minutes">minutes!</string>
    <string name="start_game">Start game</string>
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="language">Language</string>
    <string name="gamma">Gamma</string>
    <string name="save">Save</string>
    <string name="reset">Reset</string>
    <string name="tutorial">Tutorial</string>
    <string name="flashlight_description">
        Use the flashlight to shed some light into the dark.
        Some creatures may not like the light. Take care
        of the batteries or you will end up in the dark again.
    </string>
    <string name="soda_can_description">
        Drink some of this soft drink to restore your health.
    </string>
    <string name="pickaxe_description">
        This pickaxe is quite heavy. It seems quite strong
        as if it could break walls.
    </string>
    <string name="choco_milk_description">
        This choco milk smells slightly sour. This is
        definitely not the first choice!
    </string>
    <string name="apple_description">
        This apple has a worm in it. Proteins aren't that bad
        for you!
    </string>
    <string name="mate_description">
        To appear...
    </string>
    <string name="toast_description">
        To appear...
    </string>
    <string name="tutorial_text">
        The player finds himself in the middle of a maze. Its mission is to escape from this maze alive. It is very
        dark and difficult to see the path. To shed some light into the darkness a flashlight is located in the
        inventory of the player which can be accessed with [I]. By clicking on the flashlight, a brief description and
        a bigger picture of the item is displayed. An item can be dragged into the bottom bar to place it in the
        player's hand. The inventory be closed by clicking on the [X] in the upper right part of the window or by
        pressing [I] again. You may activate the previously stored item in the bottom inventory bar with your mouse
        wheel. Alternatively, the number keys on the keyboard can be used. To use an item click the left mouse button
        or the button in the inventory. Using the active item will turn the flashlight on and off, consume food or hit
        something with the pickaxe. With the right mouse button objects can be thrown away.

        The player can move forward, to the left, backward and to the right with [W, A, S, D]. With [Ctrl] the player
        can run, with [Shift] he can sneak with [Spacebar] he can jump and with [Esc] the game can be paused.

        On the ground, the player will find other items that he may collect with the left mouse button. To do so, the
        player has to look at the item and click on the item in a short distance.

        While looking for an exit from the maze the player will notice that the walls of the maze move, portals are
        placed inside the maze that teleport the player into another maze and ghosts that can hurt him but also help
        him.

        There are many different ghosts that differ from each other in their behavior. The player's task is to study
        this behavior in order to increase his chances to find out of the maze alive. Not every ghosts exists in every
        maze. Some ghosts can cause severe damage to the player, while others can heal him. Some are afraid of light,
        while others follow the player.

        Have fun with the whims of the ghosts!
    </string>
</locale>
